AXEL SOTELO

SYSTEMS ENGINEER

DESCRIPTION

Software Developer with 4+ years of experience specialized in web solutions principally in the Front-end side. Proficient in various web frameworks and libraries like angular (principal framework) and react, specialized in JavaScript/TypeScript, databases SQL and no SQL, technologies for CI/CD. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate as part of a team.

SKILLS

BASE TECH

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Node.js
- TypeScript

FRAMEWORKS AND TOOLS

- Angular (13-15-17-18)
- Jasmine
- RXJS
- Express.js
- Docker
- React
- Git
- AWS
- Gulp - Jenkins
- WebPack
- SASS

DATA BASE

- SQL Server
- MongoDB

AGILE

- Scrum
- Scrumban

LANGUAGES

- English: Fluent - Spanish: Native

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER CBTW | MAY 2024 - Present

Perform as a front-end developer for a travel services company in canada. my responsabilities are gather requeriments and bussiness needs, design and generate a web ui solution using Angular 17. Review codebase in order to suggest improvements. Also participate in code reviews related to ui project.

Tech Stack: JavaScript, TypeScript, scss, Angular 17, Azure devops, Angular material, RXJS.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER SoftServe INC | JUL 2022 - DEC 2023

Performed as a front-end engineer for a web cyber security project, Principally migrating an AngularJS project to Angular 15, my responsibilities were documenting, designing and providing solutions to migrate components/services/directives and JavaScript code to TypeScript

Tech Stack: JavaScript, TypeScript, Less, Angular JS, Angular 15, Angular 17, GitHub, Jasmine, ngx-bootstrap, RXJS.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Rockwell Automation | NOV 2021 - JUN 2022

Performed as a full-stack engineer for a web SAAS project, focusing on the requirements described by architects and giving feedback about the research done. Also, using typescript as primary language for backend and frontend (Angular), Jenkins as CI/CD software with docker (dev) and kubernetes (prod)

Tech Stack: JavaScript, TypeScript, Sass, Angular 13, Express, Node.js, Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, WebSockets, Jasmine, Chai, SonarQube, Git Lab

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Pragma | JAN 2020 - OCT 2021

Performed as a front-end developer using Web Sphere Portal system (before known as IBM Web Sphere Portal), my responsibilities were developing the content portal needs, using vanilla web (JavaScript, HTML, CSS) and depending the situation, develop web with Angular also integrating the developed app with the content manager

Developed new web applications for users of a Bank's portal (over 1k Articles published and over 1k visits per week), Other sites are visited by people around the country

Tech Stack: Angular 13, Java8 with Spring, SQL server, MongoDB, Docker, Jenkins, Git Lab, IBM BPM, EC2, HTML, CSS, JS, Sass, TS, Gulp, IBM WebSphere Portal, Node.js, Azure DevOps

CONTACT

La Ceja, Colombia (GMT-5) axelsotelo26@hotmail.com +57 3044664040

EDUCATION

UNIVERSIDAD PONTIFICIA BOLIVARIANA

Bachelor of science in Systems Engineering
JAN 2015- OCT 2020

LINKEDIN

https://www.linkedin.com/in/axel-sotelo-grajales